（法語）我有…
- 你有…         - 你有…
- 他有…         - 他有…
- 我們有…         - 我們有…
- 他們有…         - 他們有…
- 你們有…         - 你們有…
- 他們有…        - 他們有…
《環形使者》
Time travel has not yet been invented.
雖然時間旅行現在尚未被發明
But 30 years from now, it will have been.
但三十年後就會出現
It will be instantly outlawed...
它一出現  即被認定為非法
...used only in secret by the largest criminal organizations.
只被大型犯罪組織秘密使用
美國堪薩斯州    2044年
It's nearly impossible to dispose of a body in the future.
由於將來基因標誌技術的發展
I'm told. Tagging techniques, whatnot.
想處理掉一具屍首幾乎是不可能的
So when these criminal organizations in the future need someone gone...
所以  當未來的犯罪組織想把誰做掉時
...they use specialized assassins in our present called loopers.
他們要雇傭一些活在當下的特殊殺手"環形使者"
And so my employers in the future nab the target
於是  我在未來的老闆只需抓住目標
They zap him back to me, their looper.
把他傳送回來給我  他們的"環形殺手"
He appears, hands tied and head sacked.
目標會被反綁雙手  頭被套住
And I do the necessaries.
我幹完收尾工作
Collect my silver.
拿走屬於我的傭銀
So the target is vanished from the future...
這個人就在未來永遠消失了
...and I've just disposed of a body that technically does not exist.
而我只是處理掉了一個嚴格意義上來說並不存在的人
Clean.
乾淨俐落
(法語)- 早上好啊  喬         - 早上好  碧垂斯
- How's the French?           - Slow.
- 法語學得怎麼樣了？ - 進步很慢
- How's the coffee?        - Burnt.
- 咖啡怎麼樣？ - 剛煮好的
（當鋪）
（請將槍置於此箱）
Two, Jed.
兩個  傑德
Hey, Joe.
嗨  喬
- Be at the club tonight?        - Yeah.
- 晚上去夜店嗎？   - 去
Four, Jed.
四個  傑德
（法語）很高興…
很高興見到你
你好  小姐
嘭
Hey, walk around.
你繞過去
Around the bike. I'm not kidding! Wide, around, you shit!
繞過我的車  我不是開玩笑的  滾遠點
Rude! If you had a mama, she didn't raise you right.
有娘生沒娘養的傢伙
That's funny. I'm going to pick your mother up later on my bike...
笑死人了  我一會兒就用摩托載上你媽
- and I'm gonna take my blunderbuss...        - Hey, Seth.
- 再用我的雷筒短槍…    - 嗨  塞思
- Hey, Joe.        - That's new.
- 嗨  喬     - 買新車啦？
Yeah, thanks.
嗯  謝了
Goddamn thing won't fucking start.
操  又他媽發動不起來了
So you going to the Belle?
去"百麗"夜店？
- So you bought a slat bike?        - Yup.
- 你買了輛滑板摩托？ - 沒錯
How much that thing set you back? How much?
那玩意值不少錢吧？值多少？
I was gonna pull up in it tonight.
本來打算今晚騎著拉風一下的
Well, congratulations. You're pulling up with me instead.
你現在坐我車裡也挺拉風的啊
Don't. If we're going in, don't do that.
別  等我們到地方  你就別耍這個了
- Chicks dig TKs.        - They do not.
- 妞都迷會念力驅動的人啊   - 你想多了
- Yes, they do.          - It's tacky. Don't do it.
- 她們就是喜歡   - 太沒風度了  別玩這個
About 10 percent of the population has this TK mutation.
十分之一的人生來就能以念力驅物
When it first appeared,
這種特異功能第一次被發現時
everyone thought we were gonna get superheroes.
大家都以為找到了超能英雄
But it turns out this was it. Now it's a bunch of assholes...
但現在看來  他們只是一幫蠢貨
...think they're blowing your mind floating quarters.
自以為能讓硬幣飄起來就能泡遍天下的妹子
It's like this whole town.
整座城市的人都這樣
Big heads, small potatoes.
人人自命不凡  命命皆如草芥
- Full house tonight, Joe.        - We'll stick backstage.
- 今天場滿了  喬    - 我們就去後臺看看
- Just meeting up.        - Packing your blunderbusses?
- 見個人就走     - 又帶了槍？
- Hardly. Right, Seth?        - I'm with Joe.
- 沒有  對吧  塞思    - 我和喬一起
- Just meeting up, in and out.        - Go on.
- 見個人馬上就走    - 去吧
Suzie!
蘇西
- Hey!        - You working a shift tonight?
- 嘿     - 你今天輪班？
- Yeah.        - Yeah?
- 嗯    - 嗯？
A gat man bought me out already for the night.
但今晚已經有人要帶我出場了
Sweetie, I've got to work.
親愛的  我要工作了
Hey, Joe.
喬
- What?        - Zach. He's in there right now with Abe.
- 怎麼了？    - 紮克  他和亞伯在一起
- For what?        - Closed his loop.
- 怎麼了？    - 他封環了
No shit?
不是吧？
There's a reason we're called loopers.
我們之所以叫"環形使者"是因為
When we sign up for this job, taking out the future's garbage...
當我們決定做這行  幫未來掃清障礙時
...we also agree to a very specific proviso.
我們同時也簽下了一條非常特別的協議
Time travel in the future is so illegal...
在未來  時間旅行是非法的
...that when our employers want to close our contracts...
所以當老闆想終止與我們的合同時
...they'll also want to erase any trace of their relationship with us ever existing.
他們也想一次性抹掉與我們有關的任何痕跡
So if we're still alive 30 years from now...
因此如果三十年後我們還有幸不死
...they'll find our older self, zap him back to us...
他們會找到將來的我們  並送還回來
...and we'll kill him like any otherjob.
然後我們就會像幹掉其他人一樣幹掉自己
This is called closing your loop.
這就是所謂的"封環"
You get a golden payday, you get a handshake...
傭銀會變成傭金  大家會跟你握手道別
...and you get released from your contract.
你從此自由了
Enjoy the next 30 years.
好好享受接下來的三十年吧
This job doesn't tend to attract the most forward-thinking people.
所以那些想活命的人都對這工作敬而遠之
So we celebrating?
那咱們開始慶祝吧？
Look out!
小心！
（法語）早啊  喬
（法語）很高興見到你  碧垂斯
（法語）哎呀  進步神速啊
What, fourth loop closed this month?
這個月都有四個封環的了？
Loop closed. Here we go.
封環成功！幹！
Loop closed, baby!
封環成功  寶貝
Seth?
塞思
Jesus.
天啊
They could be here any minute.
他們隨時都會來的
- Are they here?        - No. Who?
- 他們不在吧？ - 沒  你說誰？
Oh, Christ. Joe, Christ!
天哪  喬  天哪
- What are you doing?        - Give me the gun.
- 你要幹嘛？ - 把槍給我
Oh, right. That's smart.
好  明智的做法
- Get away from the window.        - Christ, Joe.
- 離窗子遠點    - 天哪  喬
- Just quiet down.        - You can protect me.
- 安靜點    - 你會保護我吧？
- So they...        - What did you do?
- 這樣他們…   - 你怎麼了？
Oh, jeez. This is like a nightmare.
天哪  真是場噩夢
This is a nightmare.
這真是場噩夢
I knew then what he did, so I don't know why I asked.
我突然明白他怎麼了  我不懂自己為什麼還要問他
What did you do?
你怎麼了？
He... He was singing.
他…他在唱歌
Through the gag and sack, but I could hear the tune.
雖然罩了麻袋  我還是能聽出調子
Deep memories...
我還記得…
...my mom in a dark room taking care of me, singing that tune.
那是以前我媽晚上哄我的時候給我唱的歌
Once I knew he was me....
我知道他就是我…
Joe, I couldn't.
喬  我下不了手
I couldn't. I had to see.
我做不到  我必須得看看我自己
He told me... I remember, he told me...
我記得  他和我說…
...there's a new holy terror boss man in the future...
在未來來了一個可怕的新老大
...and he's closing all the loops.
他要封掉我們所有人的環
The Rainmaker, they call him.
大家叫他"喚雨師"
He told me it. Then he wanted a cigarette.
他說完後  又說他想抽根煙
So I untied him, and he gives me this look.
我給他松了綁  他就那樣看了我一眼
And he just starts running.
然後他就跑了
I had my blunderbuss...
我握著雷筒短槍
...so I know I've got about 15 strides until he's out of my range.
知道他一旦跑出15步遠  我就殺不了他了
And they come and they go...
我不知道該怎麼辦
...and I just watch him until he's gone.
就這麼看著他逃了
This is called letting your loop run.
這就是所謂的"失環"
It's not a good thing.
絕對不是件好事
What do I do?
我該怎麼辦？
You're the only friend I've got, Joe. You've got to help me.
你是我唯一的朋友  你要幫我
You're a fucking idiot coming here.
你來我這兒就太他媽傻了
You can't be here. I'll give you some money. That's it.
你不能呆在這兒  我給你些錢  你趕緊走
Joe! A little money? Where am I gonna go?
給我些錢？我能去哪兒？
You hop a freight train. You beat it the hell out of town.
你找輛貨車  趕緊出城
Just don't move.
別動
Tell Court, watch the window outside.
叫考爾從外面盯著窗子
You got it, window.
好的
- Kid Blue, Joe! Come on!        - Just a minute!
- 我是藍小子  喬  開門    - 等一下
- Open this goddamn door!        - I can't do anything for you, Seth.
- 他媽的快開門！    - 我幫不了你  塞思
You've got to hide me! Please, Joe! Hide me!
把我藏起來  求你了  喬
Please! Just buy me some time and then I'll go! Please?
給我點時間  我馬上就走  求你了
You gonna make me blow this door down?
你想讓我把門砸了麼？
Yeah, hold on!
馬上來
Please?
求求你
Move. Move.
過來
Come on, Joe! Open up!
快點  喬  開門
Jesus.
天啊…
- That took a while.        - You think it's easy looking this good?
- 你小子夠久的啊   - 起來不用時間嗎？
Tye's gonna watch your apartment while we go have a talk with Abe.
泰伊會幫你看房子  你跟我去見亞伯
There's coffee in the tin.
罐子裡有咖啡
Thank you.
謝了
Give me two minutes.
給我兩分鐘
Know why they call that pea shooter of yours a blunderbuss?
你知道為什麼這玩意兒叫雷筒短槍嗎？
Because it's impossible to hit anything farther than 15 yards.
因為它射不中15碼以外的靶子
Impossible to miss anything closer.
但也不可能射偏15碼以內的
It's a gun for fuck-up turkeys.
這是標準的蠢貨配槍
Not like a gat.
不像我這把手槍
A gat has range.
手槍有射程
Accuracy.
也有精准度
Kid, cut it out. Don't blow your other foot off.
別玩了  不然你另一條腿也要廢了
- Fuck!        - What the hell is going on out there?
- 操    - 他媽的外面鬧什麼呢？
- How you doing, Abe?        - Hey, Joe.
- 最近還好嗎  亞伯？ - 嘿  喬
You didn't shoot your other foot off, did you, Kid?
小子  你沒把另一條腿也打殘吧？
All right.
沒事了
My great-grandfather told my grandfather, "Men are like spiders."
我曾祖父對我祖父說過   "男人是蜘蛛"
"It's the little ones you've got to be careful of."
"越是小個子  你越要小心"
Don't know I agree with that.
這句我沒聽明白
Yeah?
是麼？
What the fuck did my great-grandfather know?
我曾祖父又他媽知道什麼呢？
This man is from the future.
這個男人來自未來
He was sent back here by the mob, a one-way ticket, to run the loopers.
他被頭頭派來這兒管理環形使者  他自己是永遠回不去了
That's low effort, even for Abe, so to pass the time...
對亞伯來說  這工作不費吹灰之力  為了打發時間...
...he recruited some real muscle, the gat men. Now he runs the city.
他招了些壯漢  叫做"槍手"  他是炙手可熱的人物
Any other city, that would be impressive.
不僅這兒  所有的城市都歸他管
How can you kids stand to wear those chokers?
你們這些小鬼怎麼能受得了這個繞脖子的東西？
- Cravats?        - Ties.
- 這個領巾    - 是領帶
Ridiculous. You're aware we don't have a dress code?
沒必要啊  我們又不要求穿正裝
- Fashion.        - You know... Well, you don't know.
- 潮嘛    - 你知道…好吧  你不知道
The movies that you're dressing like are just copying other movies.
你按電影裡的穿  這些電影也都是互相抄的
These goddamn 20th century affectations.
都是些20世紀的矯情玩意
Do something new.
來點有創意的吧
Put a glowing thing around your neck or use rubberized....
戴點更炫的東西  比如橡膠做的什麼…
- Just be new.        - Okay.
- 有新意就行     - 好的
- It was nice chatting with you, Abe.        - I do like you, Joe.
- 和你聊天很愉快  亞伯     - 我欣賞你  喬
But we're sure enough that Seth paid you a visit.
但我知道塞思去找過你了
- We have to do something.        - Seth?
- 而我們必須得把這事給解決了    - 塞思？
You're expecting we're gonna break your fingers with a hammer or something awful.
你肯定以為我們會用錘子敲你的手指來逼
But I'm gonna defuse that tension right now. That's not gonna happen.
但是你不用緊張  我不會那樣做的
What is gonna happen is that I'm gonna talk for a little.
我只是要和你稍微聊一聊
Not even that long.
不會很長的
And you're gonna give up your friend.
然後你就會交出你的朋友了
My friend? Seth? Sorry, I'm confused.
我朋友？塞思？對不起  我搞糊塗了
Well, then I'll talk a little.
好吧  那我們就來說一說
You know, you were the youngest looper I ever hired.
你是我雇的最年輕的環形使者
You looked goddamn ridiculous, they said.
他們都說你不怎麼正常
Blunderbuss up to here on you.
現在你有雷筒短槍了
They brought you in. I forget what for.
我忘了他們是因為什麼事把你逮進來的
Watch shop.
我搶了手錶店
Yeah. You rolled one of our fronts, a watch shop.
對  你偷了我們的一家店
And they had you, you know. This kid, like an animal.
他們抓了你  你這個小鬼看起來特別野
But you looked at me, your hair stuck to half your face...
你盯著我  頭髮擋住了半邊臉
...just one eye looking at me. I could see...
我只能看到你用一隻眼睛盯著我
...like seeing it happen on the TV, the bad version of your life.
就跟看電視一樣  我能看到你最糟的樣子
Like a vision, I could see how you'd turn bad.
我都可以看到你是如何一步步變壞的
So I changed it.
所以我改變了這一切
I cleaned you up and put a gun in your hand.
我幫你打理乾淨  給了你把槍
- I gave you something that was yours.        - I'm grateful for that, Abe.
- 我給你的  都是你本該有的    - 我很感激你  亞伯
I gave you something that was yours.
我給你的  都是你本該有的
And I remember that kid.
我記得那小鬼
And I think if you ask yourself, you ask,
因此我想  如果你問自己
"Who would I sacrifice for what's mine?"
"為了那些本就是我的東西  我願意犧牲誰？"
I think Seth would be deep and cozy inside that circle.
塞思肯定是一個好選擇
I'll show you how much I know you.
我要讓你看看我有多瞭解你
I'm not even gonna break you. I'm just gonna set you back a ways.
我不會毀了你  只是會將你打回原形
We know that you've been stashing half your bars.
我知道你把一半的酬金都藏起來了
Which is smart, no law against it. You're gonna get out.
很聰明  沒誰規定說不行  你總有天會金盆洗手
You're gonna go overseas. Is it right? Studying up your Mandarin?
到海外去  對不對？還在學中文？
- French.        - French?
- 法語    - 法語？
You give him up or you give us half your stash.
交出塞思  或者交出你這一半酬金
You willing to dump your silver in the dirt for Seth?
為了塞思  你甘心丟掉這一切嗎？
You're gonna kill him.
你會殺了他麼？
Not if we can help it. Be too cataclysmic a change for the future.
如果別無他法  這對未來會造成毀滅性的改變
What we'll do is dangerous in that regards...
我們要做的事是很危險的
...though not as dangerous as killing him.
不過不殺他更危險
On top of which, a man from the future runs free long enough...
最重要的是  如果放任那個未來的人潛逃太久
...this time travel shit fries your brain like an egg.
穿越時空把你的腦袋壓得像煎蛋似的
Why the fuck French?
為什麼學法語？
I'm going to France.
我要去法國
- You should go to China.        - I'm going to France.
- 你應該去中國    - 我要去法國
I'm from the future. You should go to China.
我是從未來回來的  你應該去中國
- I'm going to France.        - You're going....
- 我要去法國    - 你該去…
The floor safe, under the rug.
在地毯下的保險箱
Six seven four two.
密碼是 6742
It's the little ones that get you.
小個子的才會扳倒你
Why don't you kill an hour, Joe. On the house.
喬  你先在這裡逛會吧
Call the doc.
叫醫生準備好
15分鐘內
趕到外爾街75號
Wait.
等等！
Wait!
Wait.
等等…
You know, I can't remember my mother's face.
我記不清我媽媽的臉了
She used to run her hands through my hair.
只記得她用手撫摸我的頭髮
Just like this.
就像這樣…
I think I just let my best friend get killed tonight.
我今晚剛害死了我最好的朋友
For silver.
為了錢
Shit.
見鬼
Yeah.
耶
Shit.
真是見鬼
Sorry.
抱歉
I'm gonna give you some money.
我給你些錢
I've been stashing my silver for years and I'm gonna give you half of it.
這些年我存了些錢  我給你一半
You can raise your kid right.
你就可以不做這行了
You wanna give me half your silver?
你要分我一半的銀子？
Silver's got strings. I got my job.
銀子是有用  但我有我的工作…
You got yours.
你也有你的工作
It's sweet of you to worry about me, but I'm doing fine.
謝謝你為我著想  不過我幹得挺好的
Why don't we just stick to services rendered.
這種單純的服務關係不是很好嗎？
Is this what you want?
這不就是你想要的嗎？
"跳上火車出城去  快跑"
There's 24 there. I'm keeping count.
有24塊  我數過了
Two more trips should just do it.
再來兩趟就行了
Goddamn it!
操！
Kid, I'm sorry! Tell Abe I'm gonna fix this!
對不住了  跟亞伯說我能搞定
Tell him I'm gonna find my loop and I'm gonna kill him! Tell Abe...
我一定能找到他   我一定會殺了他…
上海
Shit!
操！
You got any aspirin?
有阿司匹林麼？
All of them, please.
全要了  謝謝
I'll take that coat, too.
這外套也要了
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
What are you doing? Joe, I told you to run.
喬  你在做什麼？我不是叫你快跑嗎？
Don't do it, you idiot.
別犯傻  你個白癡
Fucking Kid Blue.
該死的藍小子
About two more trips should do it.
還有兩趟就行了
Shit.
媽的
You stupid little shit.
你個傻逼
Pound the pavement, sweep the train yard.
從人行道過去  搜查火車場
Every second that passes is bad. Get on it.
一秒也不能耽誤！快！
Stupid little shit.
廢物
I can fix this.
我可以補救
- I can find him!        - Go home.
- 我會找到他的   - 回去
Let the grownups work.
還是讓大人們來吧…
Kid Blue.
藍小子
You bastard. How do I find you?
你個混蛋  怎樣才能把你找出來？
列印中
去找碧垂斯
Coffee?
咖啡？
Please.
謝謝
Black. And some water.
黑咖啡  再來些水
Anything else?
還要什麼？
We eating?
在這裡吃東西嗎？
- I ordered something.        - Steak and eggs. Rare and scrambled.
- 我已經點過了    - 牛排配雞蛋
Two steak and eggs, coming up.
兩份牛排配雞蛋  兩位稍等
Must hurt.
一定很疼
- I wasn't sure you'd remember her.        - I put it together.
- 我不確定你是否記得她    - 慢慢就想起來了
Clever.
聰明
You know, there's another girl who works here on the weekends.
這兒還有個週末上班的姑娘
- Jen?        - Right. Less letters.
- 珍妮？   - 對  筆劃少些
That'd be better.
更省事
How's your French coming?
法語學得怎麼樣了？
Good. You gonna tell me I ought to be learning Mandarin?
還行  你要跟我說你怎麼學的普通話嗎？
I never regretted learning French.
我從未後悔學了法語
I know you have a gun between your legs.
我知道你雙腿間藏了把槍
No? Well, you'll get it eventually.
不懂？好吧  你以後會懂的
- Obviously.        - All right, listen.
- 當然    - 好了  聽著
This is a hard situation, but we both know how this has to go down.
現在是一個困局  但我們都事態將會如何發展
I can't let you walk away from this diner.
這次我不能再放你活著出去了
This is my life now. I earned it. You had yours already.
這是我的生活  我掙來的  你已經享受過你的了
So why don't you do what old men do and die? Get the fuck out of my way.
你為什麼不願意像其他人一樣去死呢？別擋我的路
Why don't you take your gun out from between your legs and do it?
那就把你腿間的槍拔出來動手吧
Boy.
小子
It's hard staring into your eyes.
很難直視你的眼睛
- It's too strange.        - Your face looks backwards.
- 感覺太詭異了    - 你的臉讓我看到了過去
So you know what's gonna happen? You've done all this already?
那你知道將來會發生什麼嗎？你不是都經歷過了嗎？
I don't want to talk about time travel shit.
我不想提時間旅行這些爛事
If we start talking about it, we're gonna be here all day.
一旦說起來  三天三夜都講不完
Making diagrams with straws.
還得一邊說一邊給你畫圖示意
- It doesn't matter.        - I hurt myself, it changes your body.
- 這不重要    - 如果我受傷  你的身體也會出問題
- Does what I do change your memories?        - It doesn't matter!
- 我現在做的事會改變你的記憶嗎？  - 這不重要
My memory is cloudy.
我的記憶很模糊
It's a cloud.
像一團迷霧
Because my memories aren't really memories.
因為我的記憶並不是真實的記憶
They're just one possible eventuality now.
現在它們只是變成了一種可能性
And they grow clearer or cloudier as they become more or less likely.
它們或者漸漸清晰  或者因可能性變小而更加模糊
But then they get to the present moment, and they're instantly clear again.
但當它們變成當下時  就會突然又變清晰了
I can remember what you do after you do it.
我會很清楚你做過的每件事
And it hurts.
很疼
So even when we're apart...
所以現在即使我們分開
- you can remember what I do after?        - Yes.
- 我做了什麼你也一清二楚嗎？   - 對
But this is a precise description of a fuzzy mechanism.
但這只是對一個模糊機制的理智描述
It's messy.
真的一片混亂
All I know... I know two things.
我所知道的  只有兩件事
I know what's happening in my head. And I know that you're gonna meet her.
我只知道我知道的  我知道你還會遇見她
Who?
誰？
She's gonna save your life.
她會拯救你的生命
For a long time, she thought we'd....
她一直都希望…
We'd have a baby.
我們能有個孩子
She'd have been a great mother.
她會成為一個好母親的
- She wanted it so much.        - Yeah, but she...?
- 她是多麼的希望   - 但是她…？
How...?
怎麼了？
So she saves my life?
你說她救了我？
Yes.
是的
Let's take a look at your life.
看看你活成了什麼樣
You're a killer. And a junkie.
你是個殺手  一個癮君子
A fucking child mentality.
還他媽的心智不成熟
"What's mine." "My life." Save your life. You're asking me how?
什麼叫我的命？不是救了你的？還問我怎麼救的？
The question is why. Why would someone sacrifice their life?
問題是為什麼有人會甘願犧牲自己？
Cut your high and mighty bullshit. I don't need my life...
少廢話  我不需要我的生命…
Shut your fucking child mouth.
你他媽的給我閉嘴
You're so self-absorbed and stupid.
你又蠢又自以為是
And she's gonna clean you up and she's gonna....
她會蕩滌你的心靈  她會…
You're gonna take her love like a sponge.
你就像塊海綿  吸幹了她的愛
And you think, "Maybe I'm clear of the past.
你認為  "我已經跟過去徹底劃清界限了"
Maybe I'm safe."
"我應該安全了"
Yesterday.
直到昨天…
Yesterday what?
昨天怎麼了？
Thirty years from now is yesterday.
我說的昨天是30年後的昨天
You're not gonna remember it.
你要記住它
I'm gonna tell you what happens...
我會告訴你
...to this beautiful woman who saves your worthless fucking life.
這個拯救了你垃圾人生的美麗女人遭受了什麼
Have you heard of the Rainmaker?
聽說過喚雨師嗎？
Yeah, Seth said that night.
聽過  那天晚上塞思說過
New boss in the future? He used the words "holy terror."
未來的新老大  說是"極度恐怖".
Yeah. A reign of terror.
沒錯  恐怖統治
Mass executions. Vagrant purges. Everywhere at once.
大規模處決  遍地搜索  清除流浪者
Legend is the Rainmaker came out of nowhere.
最恐怖的是  沒人知道他的來頭
In the span of six months, he took total control of the five major syndicates.
僅僅半年  他就完全掌握了五個核心財團
- That'd take an army.        - He didn't have an army.
- 那需要軍隊才行    - 但他沒有軍隊
The story is that he did it alone.
傳說他一直是孤身一人
- Alone alone.        - So how did he do it?
- 單槍匹馬   - 那他是怎麼做到的？
That's the mystery. There's no pictures of him. Even if it is a him. It's insane.
這是個謎  沒人見過他的相片  甚至連性別都不知道
There are stories he has a synthetic jaw, saw his mom shot, shit like that.
他的人造下巴  他曾親眼目睹母親被殺之類的傳聞
Word spread through the ex-looper grapevine...
都是那些已解約的環形使者傳出來的
...because the first thing he did was start closing loops. All of them.
因為他做的第一件事就是封環  封所有人的環
You know what this is? This number?
你知道這是什麼嗎？這組數字？
Dale, wait. Slow down.
等等  慢點說
It could lead us to the Rainmaker, Joe! It's in the hospital records.
這可以幫我們找到喚雨師  喬  這是在醫院記錄裡找到的
Write this down: 0, 7, 1 , 5, 3...
你記下來  0, 7, 1, 5, 3,
9, 0, 2, 9, 3, 5!
...9, 0, 2, 9, 3, 5!
This is a piece of identifying information on the Rainmaker.
這是可以驗證喚雨師身份的資訊
He's here. He lives here now. In this county.
他就在這兒  就住在這個鎮子裡
And I'm gonna use this to find him.
我會用這個找到他
And I'm gonna kill him.
然後殺了他
I'm gonna stop him from killing my wife.
阻止他殺害我的妻子
Fuck you. And your wife. None of this concerns me.
去你的！還有你老婆！這事跟我一點關係都沒有
- This is gonna happen...        - It happened to you.
- 這也是你的事…     - 這是你的事
It doesn't have to happen to me. You got her picture right there in my watch?
不是我的！你把她的相片放在我的懷錶裡了？
Show me the picture. As soon as I see her, I walk away.
給我看看她的相片  等我遇到她  我馬上走開
I'll fucking marry someone else. Promise.
我他媽的和別人結婚  我保證
When I see that picture, that fog inside your brain should just...
所以只要我看到那照片  你霧濛濛的腦子裡…
...swallow up all the memories, right? She'll be gone.
關於她的記憶就會立刻消散  對嗎？她就會消失
- If you give her up, she'll be safe.        - Give her up?
- 你別管她  她就安全了    - 別管她？
Yeah, give her up! You're the one that got her killed.
對  不管她  就是因為你她才會死
If she never meets you, she's safe.
如果她從沒遇見你  她就會很安全
You don't understand. We don't have to give her up.
你不懂  我們不能不管她
I'm not gonna give her up. I'm gonna save her.
我不會不管她  我一定要救她
Get to the fields. We can lose them in the fields.
往田裡跑  就能甩掉他們
Hop a train. Get out of town!
找輛火車！離開這兒！
What the hell is everybody doing? You wait for my signal!
你們都他媽的在幹嘛？都等我的信號
- Out back! He's running!        - He ran out the back!
- 在後面  他跑了    - 他往後跑了
Shit!
媽的
Alive!
要活的
Fuck! Shit! Come on, come on!
操！廢物！快點！
Come on, you piece of shit! Come on!
快點！你個廢物！
- Get the tracker! The tracker!        - Go! Go!
- 拿追蹤器來！追蹤器！  - 快！快！
Fuck! Fuck!
操！操！
Shit.
媽的
Come on, baby. Time to get up.
寶貝  該起床了
Listen up, fucker!
聽好了  混蛋
I have shot and buried three vagrants in the past year!
去年我殺了三個流浪漢
So I don't care what hobo sob story you've got.
我不管你無家可歸的故事有多感人
I get a dozen a week, pal. It cuts no cash with me.
我每週都要聽很多  老娘不買帳
But if you show your face here again, I will cut you the fuck in half!
如果你敢再在這裡出現  我他媽會把你打成兩截
Well, you found him.
你找到他了
Tracking Seth's bike, that was clever.
追蹤塞思的摩托信號  很聰明嘛
Then you rustled up a posse and went out to get him.
然後你就搞了一幫人去抓他
- I could do it again.        - You can fuck up again? Really?
- 再給我一次機會   - 讓你再搞砸一次嗎？
I've got too much riding, Kid.
我有點不耐煩了  小子
I can't afford a fuck-up playing cowboy.
我可用不起一個隻會壞事的牛仔
Put your gat on the table.
把手槍放桌上
I wanted you to say I did good.
我只是希望你能誇我一次
That's all I wanted.
我想要的就這麼多
This is all I have.
我能做的也就這麼多
Please give me one more chance?
求你再給我一次機會
I'll bring him here alive and hold him.
我會把他活著帶回來…
And you can put a bullet in his brain yourself.
你可以親手殺了他
No!
不
Hey, who's there?
喂  是誰？
Stop right there! I will shoot you.
別動  不然我開槍了
You stop! Stop right there!
站住！不許動！
I'm telling you to stop! You stop!
我說站住！站住！
（請幫幫啞巴  食物  上帝保佑你）
Head's splitting apart.
頭快裂了
- My head.        - Hey.
- 我的頭   - 嘿
Look up at the light. Look up at me.
抬頭看看燈  看著我
How long since you dropped?
你上次滴完是什麼時候？
- Dropped?        - Dropped.
- 滴什麼    - 滴眼液
- A day.        - A day.
- 一天前    - 一天前
I can't feel my legs.
我的腿沒知覺了
You're going through withdrawal, you fucking junkie.
那是因為你毒癮上來了
You gotta help me. I'm gonna die.
幫幫我  我要死了
I'm thirsty.
我很渴
Water. Water!
水  水
Thirsty....
渴
Cid!
希德
Come inside, baby.
進去  寶貝
- Who is that man?        - He's just a vagrant.
- 那人是誰？    - 是個流浪漢
- No, he's not.        - Oh, yeah?
- 不  他不是    - 是嗎？
His shoes are too shiny.
他的鞋太亮了
Aren't you a smart monkey.
真是個聰明的小子
- Is he sick?        - Yup.
- 他病了嗎？  - 是的
- Will he get better?        - Yeah.
- 他會好起來嗎？  - 會的
- Promise?        - Just go to sleep, okay, baby boy?
- 你確定？ - 好好睡吧  好嗎  寶貝？
- Night, sweetie.        - Night, Sara.
- 晚安  小可愛    - 晚安  薩拉
Hey!
嘿
The first time I saw her face.
我第一次見她…
First time I saw her face.
Look at me.
看著我
No.
不
The first time I saw her face.
我第一次見她…
The first time I saw her face. The first time I saw your face.
我第一次見她   我第一次見她
The first time I saw her face.
我第一次見她
Morning, monkey. Do you want something to eat?
早上好  想吃什麼？
The man is up.
那人起來了
Is he staying here now?
他會留在這裡嗎？
No.
不會
Toss it.
把槍扔了
- I'm about to finish cleaning it.        - Put it down.
- 馬上就擦好了    - 把槍放下
- How are you feeling?        - I'd say I'm at 30 percent.
- 你感覺怎麼樣？    - 恢復了三成吧
You take it slow, by the end of the week you'll be at 50.
慢慢來  到週末就能恢復五成了
I took you in so you wouldn't die. You're not.
我收留你是不想讓你死  既然現在你不會死了
Take the morning to rest, then get off my farm.
你上午好好休息  然後就走吧
- I can't do that.        - I'm sorry?
- 不行    - 你說什麼？
I need to stay here for a little while.
我還要在這裡再呆一陣子
- I'm not cool with that.        - Sorry.
- 我不同意    - 我很抱歉
You just lost your "take the morning to rest" privileges.
你現在連上午在這裡休息的權利都沒了
- Get off my farm.        - No.
- 現在就給我滾    - 不行
Get off my farm.
滾出去
You couldn't scare a retarded hobo with that. Literally.
你那玩意兒都嚇不了一個智障  說實話
This is a Remington 870. One blast could cut you...
這是"雷明頓870"散彈槍  開一槍你就打成…
In half. That's telling. You're holding a gun.
打成兩半  是啊  你有槍
I say I'm not afraid, so you describe the gun to me.
我說了不怕  你還和我說這是什麼槍
It's not the gun I'm not afraid of.
倒不是說我不怕槍
What are you gonna do, shoot in the air?
你準備幹嘛？對天鳴槍嗎？
You wouldn't let me die, you're not gonna kill me.
既然你沒見死不救  就不會殺了我
So that makes me weak?
我救你一命反倒要被你要脅了？
I'm not a threat to you or your boy. I need to be on your property.
我不想傷害你和你兒子  我只是要呆在這兒
I'd rather there's no contact at all. I'm gonna stay in the fields.
但不需要和你們接觸  我就呆在地裡就行
There's one thing I need, then you'll never have to deal with me again.
只有一件事需要你幫忙  然後咱們就不需要再打交道了
Verify this is your house in the map so I'm in the right place.
你看看地圖上標的是不是你家房子  看我是否找對了地方
- What's this?        - It's a map.
- 這是什麼？    - 地圖而已
That's my house. Why is it marked?
這是我家  為什麼被標出來了？
Okay, doesn't matter. Look, I'm gonna be out of the barn in an hour.
這不要緊  聽著  我一會就走
If you can spare it, I'm gonna take this canteen.
要是你用不著  我就把這個水壺帶走
- Is there somewhere I can fill it?        - This number, how did you get this?
- 在哪兒能灌水？  - 這個號碼你怎麼會有？
That mean something to you?
你知道這號碼是什麼？
What? Hey! Hey! Hey!
怎麼了？嘿…嘿
You're right. I'm not a killer.
你說得對  我不殺人
But I'm fine with how a blast of rock salt to your face won't kill you.
但是把石鹽轟到你臉上  我眼都不會眨一下
Now you're gonna tell me who you are...
現在你該告訴我你是誰了
...and what the fuck you're doing on my farm.
你他媽到我家裡來幹嘛？
Okay.
好吧
Time travel hasn't been invented yet...
現在還沒有時間旅行這個說法
...but in 30 years, it will have been. It's gonna be used by these criminal...
但是三十年後就會有了  它將會被犯罪組織利用
You're a looper?
你是環形使者？
I can't go back to the city because Abe, the boss...
我不能回城裡
...his men will be searching for me 24/7 until they find me. Or find him.
我老闆的手下一刻不停在搜城  要把我或他找到
All I've got is that map.
我手裡只有這張地圖
He had three houses marked on it, yours is one of them.
上面標了三座房子  你家是其一
I know he's coming here.
我知道他會來的
You know about loopers? You know what we do?
你知道我們是做什麼的嗎？
So he's coming here to murder my son...
他要到這兒來殺我兒子
...because he thinks he might be this Rainmaker?
因為他認為他可能是喚雨師？
Once he kills the Rainmaker, what happens?
如果他真殺了喚雨師  會怎麼樣？
I think he thinks if he killed the Rainmaker...
我想他覺得如果他真殺了喚雨師
...he never would have been sent back.
那他就根本不會被送回來了
He'd just vanish. He'd disappear just like he appeared.
他會直接消失  就像他突然出現那樣
He'd be back with his wife.
他和他老婆又能在一起了
Who is he, this guy you let run?
被你放跑的那個傢伙是誰？
Just some random guy from the future?
只是一個未來的無關緊要的人嗎？
He's just somebody. You know what the numbers mean?
他只是個普通人  那到底是什麼號碼？
This is Cid's birthday and this is the med code of the hospital he was born in.
這是希德的生日  這是他出生的醫院的代碼
How many kids were born in that hospital that day with your son?
跟你兒子一天在那家醫院出生的小孩還有幾個？
- Like, two?        - Sounds right.
- 好像還有兩個吧？    - 估計是了
Three kids, three houses marked on his map.
他把三個孩子的家都標出來了
One of them is the Rainmaker.
他只知道其中有一個就是喚雨師
- He doesn't know which.        - What's he gonna do?
- 但不確定是哪個    - 他會怎麼做？
Oh, God.
天哪
- Can he really do this?        - Think about what doing this would fix.
- 他真的會下手嗎？  - 你想想他這樣做能改變什麼吧
What he thinks it would fix.
他以為能改變什麼
If he comes here, will you stop him?
如果他真來了  你會阻止他嗎？
- I'm asking, can I trust you?        - I don't care if you trust me.
- 我是在問  我能不能信你？   - 我不管你是否相信我
I don't care about your son.
也不管你兒子死活
I lost my life. I kill this man, I get it back.
我殺了他  我自己就能活命
He'll kill the other two kids and come here last. Put off facing me.
他會先殺了其他兩個孩子之後再過來
All this goddamn cane leaves us blind.
有這些甘蔗擋著  我們什麼都看不見
He can get within 50 yards of this place without a hawk spotting him.
他可以躲在裡面  誰都發現不了他
What makes sense is we burn the fields. Level them.
我們應該把地燒了  把雜草鏟平
How much gas you got in that barn?
你倉庫裡有多少汽油？
- No, you can't burn down my cane fields.        - This stuff is half dead anyway.
- 不行  不能燒甘蔗地   - 它們已死得差不多了
It's the seed for next year. It's not gonna happen, you fucking nut.
但是要留著為來年做種  不能燒  絕對不行
Listen, use what you need and set up anywhere.
聽著  你需要什麼儘管拿  都聽你的
But one thing: I don't want you talking to Cid.
但有一條：別和我兒子說話
I watch my son, you watch the cane.
我看好我兒子  你看好甘蔗地
- That's the deal.        - Good by me.
- 就這麼著吧     - 我沒問題
Fine.
那就好
- Jesus.        - All right, hold still.
- 天呐    - 行了  別動
It's easy for things to get infected on a farm.
在農場受傷很容易感染…
Start falling off.
傷口縫好了
Pussy.
娘娘腔
I'm out here and you're in the house. We need a way to communicate.
我在外面  你在屋子裡  我們需要一種聯繫方式
There's a dinner bell in the barn. You can ring that if someone's coming.
在倉庫裡有個晚飯鈴  如果有人來了  你就按鈴
Dinner bell. We need buzzers or walkies or something.
我們要的是蜂鳴器或對講機之類的東西
I don't know what we've got, but I'll look. Cid!
不知道有沒有  我來找找  希德
- How's the math coming?        - I want to help the man.
- 算術做得怎麼樣？  - 我想幫那個人
- Help him with what?        - I could help him with my toys.
- 用什麼幫他？   - 用我的玩具
No. Let me talk to you.
不可以  聽我說
I need you to stay away from that man. Okay?
你離那個人遠點  明白嗎？
Let him do his thing, but stick with me.
他做他的  你就呆在我身邊
- Okay?        - Is he not good?
- 明白嗎？ - 他不是好人嗎？
Well, we're gonna see what he is. All right?
我們要看看他是什麼人   好嗎？
But I need you to stick with me.
跟我呆一起就好
Good boy.
好孩子
Hand me that Phillips.
把那個夾子給我
- Tell me if you hear her coming.        - What are we doing here?
- 要是聽到她來了就告訴我    - 我們這是幹嘛？
Commundication.
做信號器
But I need to make it stronger.
這個信號還要加強
- And how do we do that?        - Bigger battery.
- 要怎麼弄？ - 用大點的電池
Smart.
聰明
Do you kill people?
你會殺人嗎？
Let's say I kill people.
算會吧…
With your gun?
用你的槍？
- You want a gun like mine?        - Yeah.
- 你也想要一把我這樣的槍？ - 嗯
What are you gonna do with it, pole vaulting? It's bigger than you.
你要槍做什麼？撐杆跳？槍比你還大
Stop bad things from happening.
阻止壞的事情發生
Shit!
媽的
So how long you and your mom been out here on the farm?
你和你媽媽在這兒住多久了？
She's not.
她不是
She's not what?
不是什麼？
Sara doesn't know, but I remember my real mom.
薩拉不知道  但我記得我真正的媽媽
When I was a baby, I couldn't stop it.
我那時候很小  我無能為力
Couldn't stop what?
對什麼無能為力？
I couldn't stop her from getting killed.
阻止我媽媽被殺
I saw it, but I couldn't stop it.
我看見了  但是我阻止不了
I wasn't strong enough.
我不夠強大
You should....
你應該…
- You should talk to your mom about this.        - She's not my mom. She's a liar.
- 你應該和你媽媽談談這個    - 她不是我媽媽  她是騙子
Spotted him coming out of a sewer tunnel on the west end. He's on the run.
我們發現他從西區的下水道裡出來   正在逃
Think he's heading to the west on Talbott Street...
他在往西塔街跑
...possibly to Whore's Alley. We have a visual.
好像是去紅燈區
You can't take that thing out with a plow or something?
你不能用犁把那樹根拉掉嗎？
Listen, I found a....
聽著  我找到…
In the barn, I found some parts and I made a thing.
我在倉庫裡找到一些零件  做了個東西
Here.
給
So if you see something, just push that.
如果你看到什麼  就按一下那個
When?
什麼時候的事？
Last night he woke me up. Don't tell him I told you. He didn't...
昨晚他過來喊我的  別說是我說的  我答應他不告訴你的
You said you were his mom.
你說你是他媽媽
Yeah.
是啊
He told me you're not.
他跟我說你不是
He said that?
他說的？
Yeah.
是
- If he's not your son, who is he?           - He's my son.
- 如果他不是你兒子  那他是誰？ - 他是我兒子
I had Cid when I was 22.
我22歲時生的他…
But I didn't want to give up my life in the city.
但我不想放棄市里的生活
So I dropped him here on the farm with my sister...
所以我把他留在這農場
...and she saw how I was living, so she took him.
我姐姐看到我當時的生活狀況  就把他接了過來
And my sister, she raised him.
然後我姐姐撫養了他
She loved him. He called her Mom.
她愛他  他叫她媽媽
How did she get killed?
她是怎麼死的？
Jesus Christ.
天啊
He remembers it. You've gotta talk to him.
他都記得  你真應該和他好好談談
I told you one thing. I told you to stay away from my son.
我告訴過你  離我兒子遠點
- He asked about my gun.        - Stay out of it!
- 他問了我槍的事    - 你別管就行
And stay the fuck away from my son!
你他媽離我兒子遠點
Where does 56 go?
56應該放哪裡？
Oh, good. You're smart.
乖  真聰明
Twenty-one?
那21呢？
How long can you not sleep?
你能多長時間不睡覺？
I don't know. Probably a while. It's a good question.
不知道…可能就一會兒吧  這個問題很好
Where does it go? Come on.
該放哪兒？快
Good.
很好
Thirty-two?
到32了
- You should help Joe watch.        - Joe?
- 我們應該幫喬一起守著   - 喬？
Because he can't stay awake all the time.
因為他不可能一直不睡
- Isn't our business. Okay?         - He's keeping us safe.
- 這跟我們沒關係  知道嗎？ - 他在保護我們的安全
Let's do this now, okay?
現在我們專心做這個  好嗎？
You have 32 there. I know you know this one.
你手上拿著32  你肯定知道該放哪裡
- No. Eight times three is what?        - Thirty-two.
- 不對  8乘以3等於幾？   - 32
Eight times three is what?
8乘以3等於幾？
Thirty-two.
- I want you to count three eights.        - Eight, sixteen...
- 你來數3個8      - 8, 16…
Thirty-two.
- You telling me you want alone time?        - No.
- 你是不是想一個人呆著了？ - 不是
Then why don't you put that where it belongs?
那你為什麼不放到對的地方呢？
- Alone time.        - He's protecting us...
- 一個人呆著吧   - 他在保護我們
...because you can't do it.
因為你做不到
- I told you to stay away from him, didn't I?        - I never did anything.
- 我告訴過你離他遠點    - 我什麼也沒做
- Do you think I'm stupid?        - So?
- 你覺得我蠢麼？    - 那又怎樣？
- I told Joe to leave...        - So?
- 我告訴過你…   - 那又怎樣？
- You do what I tell you!        - You can't tell me what to do.
- 你要按我說的做     - 你沒資格命令我
You're not my mom!
你不是我媽媽
You're not my mom! You're a liar!
你不是我媽媽  你這個騙子
You're gonna get killed because you won't stop lying!
你也會被殺掉  因為你騙人
- Cid, calm down.        - You're lying! I hate you!
- 希德  冷靜…    - 你騙我  我恨你
- You're lying to me! I hate you!        - Cid....
- 你騙我  我恨你   - 希德
- I hate you! Liar! You're lying!        - Calm down. Calm down.
- 我恨你  騙子  你騙我…   - 冷靜  冷靜
Liar!
騙子
You're not my mom! You're a liar!
你不是我媽媽  你是騙子
You're not my mom!
你不是我媽媽
I hate you!
我恨你
Liar!
騙子
Liar! Liar!
騙子  騙子
I'm sorry.
對不起
It's okay, sweetie.
沒事了  親愛的
Holy shit.
我操
Evening, ma'am.
你好  夫人
Evening. How can I help you?
你好  有事嗎？
You can start by accepting my apologies re the hour.
抱歉這麼晚來訪
- Hope I didn't catch you at supper.        - That's fine.
- 希望沒有打擾到你們的晚餐   - 沒事
I've been walking between empty farms all day.
我在太陽下走訪了好幾個空農場了
Thought I'd just tick this one off the list.
我想今天把您家一併結束了
- Not have to come back tomorrow.        - What's this about?
- 這樣明天就不用來了    - 結束什麼？
You alone here, ma'am?
你不是一個人在這兒住吧？
My husband should be back any time.
我丈夫很快會從城裡回來
Happy to hear it.
那就好
Could I trouble you for some water?
能麻煩藉口水喝麼？
I'll get you some. You can take the glass with you.
我去給你倒點  杯子你就直接帶走吧
Actually, ma'am...
抱歉  夫人
...my business today, this ticking off the list business...
我今天來是為了走訪表單上的人家
is gonna require me coming in,
必須得進屋子看看
if that's all right.
如果您不介意的話
- Will you tell me what this is about?        - I will, yes.
- 能告訴我到底是什麼事呢？ - 一定跟您說明白
Can I come in?
我能先進去嗎？
Ma'am?
夫人？
I'm a deputized police officer, looking for an escaped criminal.
我是員警  正在這片搜捕逃犯
Anyone through here in the past two days, vagrants?
這兩天有沒有在附近見過可疑人士？
Vagrants are always passing, nobody near the house.
這附近總有流浪漢四處遊蕩
That man there?
這個人有見過嗎？
He's young. No.
他很年輕啊  沒有
We're looking for his father, too. Similar looking build, late 50s...
我們也在找他的父親  他們長得很像  快60了
...may or may not be traveling together.
他們兩個可能在一起
Do you recognize them?
見過嗎？
- No.        - Keep them.
- 沒有   - 照片你留著吧
Your kids with your husband?
你孩子們和你先生在一起？
Yeah, just one.
是  我只有一個孩子
- How old?        - Ten.
- 多大了？  - 十歲
Ten....
十歲
I'm gonna show you the barn and house.
我帶你去倉庫看看  然後再來這裡
And then you can be on your way.
然後你就可以交差了
I took the liberty with your barn. Apologies.
倉庫我已經看過了  抱歉沒先打聲招呼
So the house.
現在只要看房子就行了
- Ten, you said? Your boy?        - Yeah.
- 你說你兒子10歲？    - 是的
And your husband?
你丈夫呢？
I've just gotta check in with the home office.
我把資訊傳回總部核實一下
The boy's in the city with his father. When they getting back?
你說孩子和父親都在城裡  他們什麼時候回來？
Couldn't tell you.
不好說
This goddamn thing.
破玩意
I can never get a signal this far out of town.
離城遠了就沒信號
Piece of shit.
垃圾
Okay. Here we go.
總算連上了
Is this man dangerous?
這人很危險嗎？
He shoots men down for a living. He's a stone-cold killer.
他以殺人為生  是個冷血殺手
My boss has half the city looking for him.
我老大傾半城人力在找他
Half the city and me, so....
半城人力  加上我…
And if you find him, there's a hell of a price.
如果你發現他了  能有很可觀的獎金哦
Chunk of money like that, you should think on it.
一大筆錢  你考慮一下
- I will.        - All right. Show me upstairs.
- 我會的    - 好  帶我上樓看看？
There's drafts in the house.
房子裡老是有穿堂風
My granddad built this tunnel when the vagrant raids got bad.
流浪漢鬧得厲害的時候  我爺爺挖了這條地道
- Nana said he was nuts.        - Thank you, Granddad.
- 奶奶說他瘋了   - 多虧了你爺爺
- That wasn't the man.        - No. It's funny. I know that guy, though.
- 他不是那個要殺我們的壞蛋吧？ - 不是  我還算認識他
His name is Jesse. I like him. He's good.
他叫傑西  我喜歡他  他人挺好的
He's gonna go away once he doesn't find me.
如果他找不到我  他就會走了
He won't hurt your mom.
他不會傷害你媽媽…
- Sara.        - Where's your mom?
- 我是說薩拉    - 你媽媽呢？
Where's my mom?
我媽媽呢？
She gave me up. I was younger than you.
她把我賣了  那時我比你還小
We were vagrants, and she was alone.
賣給了流浪漢  她那時候孤身一人
I thought she was stupid for getting on the drugs she was on...
以前  我老覺得她太蠢了  一直吸毒
...but now I see she was just so alone.
但我現在懂了  她只是太孤單了
It's what she had.
她一無所有
She sold me to a panhandle gang.
於是把我賣給了一個丐幫
I got away and I ran and ended up on this train.
我逃了出來  跑啊跑  最後跳上一輛火車
I remember I was sitting there in an empty car.
我記得我坐在空蕩蕩的車廂裡
And I saw myself over and over again...
我一遍遍地想像自己
...killing those men that bought me,
殺掉那些買下我的傢伙
that got my mom on what she was on.
還有那些讓我媽媽生不如死的傢伙
Just finding them and tearing them apart. Saving my mom.
找到他們  把他們撕成碎片  救出我媽媽
But you didn't.
但是你沒這樣做
No, a man in the city found me, put a gun in my hand.
城裡有個人發現了我  給了我一把槍
Gave me something that was mine.
給了我一些本屬於我的東西
That's just men trying to figure out what they would do...
世上有種人  他們知道該做什麼…
...to keep what's theirs, what they've got.
才能保護好他們的東西
That's the only kind of man there is.
要做就做這樣的人
I'm not gonna let Sara get killed.
我不會讓薩拉被殺的
I think we're clear.
我們安全了
Sara!
莎拉
Baby.
寶貝
All working girls, yeah?
這片都是夜店的妞  對嗎？
This whole block and a couple of blocks over.
這整個街區  還有那邊的幾塊都是
Hello, Joe.
你好啊  喬
If you want to check those, too, I can arrange.
那些也要看看嗎  我可以安排
I'm an arranger, stranger.
我辦事你放心
If you don't see what you want to see, no refunds.
不過就算你沒找到要找的  錢也不能退
What?
怎麼了？
What happened?
出什麼事了？
That's pretty good.
挺厲害啊
In the city, young guys would...
在城裡  那些男人
...hit on me by floating fucking quarters.
想把硬幣弄浮起來  跟我搭訕
And I wouldn't tell them I was TK...
我不說我也是念力者
...but I would keep their quarters down.
但是我會讓他們的硬幣浮不起來
This one guy just busted a blood vessel in his eye trying to get it up.
有個傢伙  眼睛的血管都爆了  也沒讓硬幣漂起來
He's you.
那個人就是你
Your loop.
他就是你的環
You lied to me.
你對我撒謊了
But I know you're not lying when you say you're gonna kill this guy...
不過我相信你沒說謊  當你說要殺了這人
...your own self.
也就是殺你自己的時候
You protected Cid from that gat man.
那個槍手在的時候  你保護了希德
- come on.       - He...
- 別說了   - 其實
- Yeah.        - He saved your ass, didn't he?
- 對    - 是他救了你的命  是嗎？
He saved my ass.
是他救了我的命
He's a....
他是個…
He's a good kid.
他是個好孩子
Yeah, he is.
是的  他很乖
You know, when I came back, after my sister died...
我回來的時候  就是我姐死了之後
...I remember seeing him...
我記得
...for the first time in two years just sitting on the porch.
兩年來第一次見到他  他就坐在門廊下
I drove up crying. I'd been at this...
我哭著開著車
...party all night in the city when I got the call...
我剛剛結束在城裡的一個派對
...so I was wearing this ridiculous party dress.
還沒來得及換衣服
All my ridiculous shit.
我看上去可笑極了
And I don't know if he...
我不知道…
...even remembered me...
不知道他是否還記得我
...but he looked at me....
但是他看著我
I abandoned him.
我拋棄了他
I abandoned my baby.
我拋棄了我的孩子
And I've seen so many men in the city...
在城裡我見過太多的人
...who I look in their eyes and they're just lost.
他們的眼神都是空洞的  眼裡只有迷茫
So whether he loves me back or not...
所以不管他愛不愛我
...as long as I'm there to raise him...
只要我還活著
...he's gonna be taken care of.
我就要好好照顧他
He's gonna be safe.
我要保護他的安全
He's never gonna get lost.
他永遠也不會迷茫
Hello, Joe.
你好啊  喬
Jesse.
傑西
Put this down and let her go.
我把槍放下  你放開她
Sara, Jesse here is the best shot with a gat that I know.
薩拉  傑西是我認識的人裡槍法最好的
When he lets you go, just sit on the couch. Don't do anything stupid.
他放開你後  你就坐下  別做傻事
He's coming here, Jess. My loop is coming here.
他要來了  傑西  我的環要來了
- I gotta take you in.        - I got 948 bars of pure silver.
- 我必須得抓你回去    - 我有948塊純銀
I close my loop, I get right with Abe.
我會封了我的環  回去找亞伯
Whatever he gives back, I'll split it with you.
不管他還給我多少  我分你一半
Was that your plan?
就這樣而已嗎？
Okay, take all of it.
好吧  我全都給你
Are you delusional? You ain't getting right.
別犯傻了  沒人會幫你的
Long as Abe's got one gat man standing he's gonna hunt you until his dying day.
只要亞伯還剩一個槍手  到死他都不會放過你
We're gonna go now. Gonna get in my truck and you're just gonna....
我們還是走吧  坐上我的卡車  這就走…
I'm sorry.
對不起
The Rainmaker....
喚雨師…
Cid!
希德
Oh, my God!
老天…
Cid!
希德
Cid?
It's him. What is he, some TK freak?
就是他  他是超強念力者嗎？
You knew.
你早就知道了
- What are you doing?        - How did your sister die?
- 你要幹嘛？ - 你姐姐怎麼死的？
- What are you doing with those guns?        - How's she die? Is that what happened to her?
- 你拿著槍要幹嘛？ - 她是不是也像剛才那樣死的？
- No!        - He kill her like that?
- 不   - 他就像那樣殺了她？
No. He was climbing a bookshelf and it fell back on him.
他當時在爬書架  書架倒下來壓住了他…
He can get scared. It exploded.
他嚇壞了  於是就爆發了
- Jesus frigging...        - He'll learn to control it.
-  天哪    - 但總有一天他會控制的
- Imagine what he's gonna do!        - If he did good with it, though.
- 想想他能造什麼孽吧   - 但是他也可能用它來做好事啊
If he grew up with me raising him.
如果他長大  控制能力也會變強吧？
If he grew up good....
如果他長大以後是個好人
He doesn't.
事實證明他不是
You stay away from him, Joe!
你別動他  喬
Cid! Stay away from Joe, baby!
希德  離喬遠點
Follow me, baby!
聽話  寶貝
Come to me. It's okay.
過來  沒事的
It's okay, baby.
沒事了  寶貝
Right now two things have happened.
現在有兩件事
My loop knows Cid's the kid he's looking for.
那個人已經知道希德就是他要找的人
And my gang knows I'm here.
還有我老闆也知道我在這裡了
That means in 15 minutes, one or both of them is coming down that highway.
也就是說  不出一刻鐘  一方或雙方就會從那條公路上過來
Pack up the truck. Take everything you can and go.
你收拾好東西  開那個槍手的車趕快走
Drive north away from the city.
一路向北  離開這兒
Thank you.
謝謝你
Got everyone here, all our men.
所有人都到齊了  集合完畢
Arm them up. Let's go.
全副武裝  立刻出發
I got him, Abe. I got him.
我抓到他了  亞伯  我抓到他了
Well, shit.
真他媽巧…
That's right, motherfuckers.
兔崽子
I got him.
我抓到他了
Knew he was sweet on this one whore.
他和一個妓女有一腿
- I checked her building...        - They found Joe...
- 我查了她住的樓…    - 他們也找到喬了
...in a farm on the east side. That's why all the gat men are here.
在東邊的一個農場裡  這就是為什麼所有人都集合了
The whole crew is arming up to make a sweep.
所有人都全副武裝  要掃平那裡
Joe?
喬？
Fuck Joe. Save your bullets! I've got the loop!
去他媽的喬  省省子彈吧  我抓到了他的環…
Not such a fuck-up now, huh? I'm bringing him up to see Abe.
現在到底是誰他媽慫了  我帶他去見亞伯
Get this asshole!
來呀  混蛋
Motherfuckers!
去你媽的
Holy shit.
我操
Joe!
喬
Guess I put the gun in that kid's hand, huh?
當年還是我教的那孩子用槍
I guess everything comes back around.
這就是現世報吧
Like your goddamn ties.
就像你那該死的領帶…
Take this truck. And take your gold and go live your life.
這車給你  帶上錢  想去哪就去哪吧
Nobody's coming after you. I fixed it.
沒人會追殺你了  我都擺平了
You go kill the boy. That how you fix it?
你是要殺了那孩子嗎？來擺平一切？
You're goddamn right I'm gonna kill that boy!
你他媽說對了  我要殺了那兔崽子
- You just got your life back.        - My life?
- 我給你撿了一條命   - 我的命？
Your life. Becoming you.
是你的命吧  好讓我變成你
Goddamn it! You've lost your fucking mind!
你他媽瘋了
You let this boy live, he's going to take everything you've got.
你現在放那孩子一馬  將來他會讓你一無所有
And everything I got!
讓我一無所有
See what he becomes.
你已經知道他以後會變成什麼樣的人
I haven't seen that yet.
我不知道
Shit.
操
Okay, baby, we're going.
好了  寶貝  我們走吧
Put your seat belt on.
系好安全帶
- Stop.        - Duck down. It's okay.
- 停車    - 臥倒  沒事的
- Stop, please. He can shoot us.        - Duck down.
- 快停車  他要開槍了    - 臥倒
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
停車 停車 停車 停車
- Cid.        - I'm sorry.
- 希德…    - 對不起
It's okay. It's okay. I'm gonna get you down.
沒事  沒事  我把你解開
Okay, we're going into the cane. Go. Go.
快躲到甘蔗地裡去  快跑
Go.
跑
No!
不
No. Cid, no.
不  希德  不要…
No!
不…
It's okay, baby. You're okay.
沒事了  寶貝  沒事了
It's okay, baby.
沒事了  寶貝
It's okay.
沒事了
I love you. Calm down.
我愛你  冷靜下來
Good boy.
乖孩子
Mommy loves you.
媽媽愛你
It's okay.
沒事了…
Mom.
媽媽
Shit.
操
You did good. You did so good. Good boy.
你做得很好  做得很好  好孩子
Listen to me. I need you to run into the fields now.
聽我說  你先到地裡去
- No, Mom, I don't want to leave you.        - It's okay.
- 不  媽媽  我不要離開你    - 沒事的
- You need to go. Go!        - Move!
- 你該走了     - 閃開
Move, goddamn it!
你他媽閃開
Move.
閃開
Then I saw it.
眼前的一切突然讓我明白了
I saw a mom who would die for her son.
一位母親為了兒子甘願死去
A man who would kill for his wife.
一個男人為了救回妻子不惜殺人
A boy, angry and alone.
一個孩子因此變得扭曲而孤獨
Laid out in front of him, the bad path. I saw it.
我看見那條毀滅之路就在他面前出現
And the path was a circle...
這條路循環往復
...round and round.
沒有盡頭
So I changed it.
我要改變這一切
Cid!
希德
Where's Joe?
喬呢？
He had to go away, baby.
他有事先走了  寶貝